<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="queries.xsl"?>
<aqd:query xmlns:dc="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-namespace/"
           xmlns:aqd="http://aurora-network.global/queries/namespace/">
    <dc:identifier type="sdg">7</dc:identifier>
    <icon>https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/content/images/E_SDG_Icons-07.jpg</icon>
    <dc:subject type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdg7</dc:subject>
    <dc:identifier type="version">5.0</dc:identifier>
    <dc:identifier type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817445</dc:identifier>
    <dc:source type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817443</dc:source>
    <dc:relation type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdgs</dc:relation>
    <dc:title>SDG-07 affordable and clean energy</dc:title>
    <dc:description>
        Energy is central to nearly every major challenge and opportunity the world faces today. Be it for
        jobs, security, climate change, food production or increasing incomes, access to energy for all is essential.
        Working towards this goal is especially important as it interlinks with other Sustainable Development Goals.
        Focusing on universal access to energy, increased energy efficiency and the increased use of renewable energy
        through new economic and job opportunities is crucial to creating more sustainable and inclusive communities and
        resilience to environmental issues like climate change.
        At the current time, there are approximately 3 billion people who lack access to clean-cooking solutions and are
        exposed to dangerous levels of air pollution. Additionally, slightly less than 1 billion people are functioning
        without electricity and 50% of them are found in Sub-Saharan Africa alone. Fortunately, progress has been made
        in the past decade regarding the use of renewable electricity from water, solar and wind power and the ratio of
        energy used per unit of GDP is also declining.
        However, the challenge is far from being solved and there needs to be more access to clean fuel and technology
        and more progress needs to be made regarding integrating renewable energy into end-use applications in
        buildings, transport and industry. Public and private investments in energy also need to be increased and there
        needs to be more focus on regulatory frameworks and innovative business models to transform the world’s energy
        systems.
    </dc:description>
    <dc:rights href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC-BY v4 INT</dc:rights>
    <dc:creator>Aurora Universities Network (AUR); René Otten (VUA); Eike Spielberg (UDE); Felix Schmidt (UDE); Maurice Vanderfeesten (VUA); Alessandro Arienzo (UNA); Roberto delle Donne (UNA); Ignasi Salvadó Estivill (URV); José Luis González Ugarte (URV); Didier Vercueil (UGA); Nykohla Strong (UAB); Eike Spielberg (UDE); Linda Hasse (UDE); Ane Sesma (UEA); Baldvin Zarioh (UIC); Friedrich Gaigg (UIN); Nicolien van der Grijp (VUA); Yasin Gunes (VUA); </dc:creator>
    <dc:contributor>Eike Spielberg (UDE); Peter van den Besselaar (VUA)
    </dc:contributor>
    <dc:date>2020-06-30</dc:date>
    <aqd:query-definitions syntax="SCOPUS">
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>1</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, ensure universal access to affordable, reliable and modern energy services
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    7.1.1
                    Proportion of population with access to electricity
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    7.1.2
                    Proportion of population with primary reliance on clean fuels and technology
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                ( ( "access" )  W/3  ( "affordable"  OR  "reliable"  OR  "modern" )  W/3  ( "energy"  OR  "electricity" ) )
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>2</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, increase substantially the share of renewable energy in the global energy mix
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    7.2.1
                    Renewable energy share in the total final energy consumption
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                ( "share"  OR  "increas*"  OR  "promot" )  W/3  ( ( "renewable"  OR  "alternative"  OR  "clean" )  W/3  ( "energy"  OR  "fuel" ) )  
				</aqd:query-line>
                 <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                ( "share"  OR  "increas*"  OR  "promot" )  W/3  ( ( "energy" )  W/3  ( "conversion"  OR  "transition" ) )  
				</aqd:query-line>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                ( "share"  OR  "increas*"  OR  "promot" )  W/3  
				( "Biofuel*"  OR  "Biogas*"  OR  "Heat pump*"  OR  "Hybrid power"  OR  "Solar energy"  OR  "Solar power"  OR  "Wind energy"  OR  "Wind farm*"  
				OR  "Wind power"  OR  "Wind turbine*" )  
				</aqd:query-line>
				</aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>3</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, double the global rate of improvement in energy efficiency
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    7.3.1
                    Energy intensity measured in terms of primary energy and GDP
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( ( " improv*" )  W/3  ( "energy" )  W/3  ( "efficiency" ) )
                </aqd:query-line>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( ( "reduc*" )  W/3  ( "energy consumption" ) )
                </aqd:query-line>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( ( "energy intensity"  OR  "energy consumption" )  W/3  ( "primary"  OR  "GDP" ) )
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>a</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, enhance international cooperation to facilitate access to clean
                    energy research and technology, including renewable energy, energy efficiency and advanced and
                    cleaner fossil-fuel technology, and promote investment in energy infrastructure and clean energy
                    technology
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    7.a.1
                    Mobilized amount of United States dollars per year starting in 2020 accountable towards the $100
                    billion commitment
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    ("energy") AND ("international" W/3 "cooperation")
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>b</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, expand infrastructure and upgrade technology for supplying modern and
                    sustainable energy services for all in developing countries, in particular least developed
                    countries, small island developing States, and land-locked developing countries, in accordance with
                    their respective programmes of support
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    7.b.1
                    Investments in energy efficiency as a percentage of GDP and the amount of foreign direct investment
                    in financial transfer for infrastructure and technology to sustainable development services
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                     ( ( ( "modern"  OR  "sustainable" )  W/3  "energy" )  AND  ( "develop* countr*"  OR  "least developed countr*"  OR  "small island*" ) )
                </aqd:query-line>
                 <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				 ( ( "investment" )  W/3  ( "energy" ) )  AND  ( "GDP" )
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:filters>
            <aqd:filter type="affilation" field="AF-ID"></aqd:filter>
            <aqd:timerange field="PUBYEAR">
                <aqd:start>2009</aqd:start>
                <aqd:end>2020</aqd:end>
            </aqd:timerange>
        </aqd:filters>
    </aqd:query-definitions>
</aqd:query>
