<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="queries.xsl"?>
<aqd:query xmlns:dc="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-namespace/"
           xmlns:aqd="http://aurora-network.global/queries/namespace/">
    <dc:identifier type="sdg">1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:subject type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdg1</dc:subject>
    <dc:identifier type="version">2.0</dc:identifier>
    <dc:identifier type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817433</dc:identifier>
    <dc:source type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817352</dc:source>
    <dc:relation type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdgs</dc:relation>
    <dc:title>SDG-01 no poverty</dc:title>
    <dc:description>More than 700 million people, or 10% of the world population, still live in extreme poverty and is struggling to fulfil the most basic needs like health, education, and access to water and sanitation, to name a few. The majority of people living on less than $1.90 a day live in sub-Saharan Africa. Worldwide, the poverty rate in rural areas is 17.2 per cent—more than three times higher than in urban areas.

Having a job does not guarantee a decent living. In fact, 8 per cent of employed workers and their families worldwide lived in extreme poverty in 2018. Poverty affects children disproportionately. One out of five children live in extreme poverty. Ensuring social protection for all children and other vulnerable groups is critical to reduce poverty.

Poverty has many dimensions, but its causes include unemployment, social exclusion, and high vulnerability of certain populations to disasters, diseases and other phenomena which prevent them from being productive. Growing inequality is detrimental to economic growth and undermines social cohesion, increasing political and social tensions and, in some circumstances, driving instability and conflicts.</dc:description>
    <dc:rights href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC-BY v4 INT</dc:rights>
    <dc:creator>
      Aurora Universities Network (AUR); Didier Vercueil (UGA); Nykohla Strong (UAB); Raf Guns (UAN); Susanne Mikki (UBE); Felix Schmidt (UDE); Jaqui Farrar (UEA); Lars Kullman (UGO); Baldvin Zarioh (UIC); René Otten (VUA); Maurice Vanderfeesten (VUA)
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:contributor>
      Eike Spielberg (UDE)
    </dc:contributor>
    <dc:date>2018-03-31</dc:date>
    <aqd:query-definitions syntax="SCOPUS">
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>1</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
          <!---->
By 2030, eradicate extreme poverty for all people everywhere, currently measured as people living on less than $1.25 a day
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.1.1
Proportion of population below the international poverty line, by sex, age, employment status and geographical location (urban/rural) </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>
          <!---->By 2030, reduce at least by half the proportion of men, women and children of all ages living in poverty in all its dimensions according to national definitions </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.2.1
Proportion of population living below the national poverty line, by sex and age </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.2.2
Proportion of men, women and children of all ages living in poverty in all its dimensions according to national definitions
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>Implement nationally appropriate social protection systems and measures for all, including floors, and by 2030 achieve substantial coverage of the poor and the vulnerable </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.3.1
Proportion of population covered by social protection floors/systems, by sex, distinguishing children, unemployed persons, older persons, persons with disabilities, pregnant women, newborns, work-injury victims and the poor and the vulnerable
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>
By 2030, ensure that all men and women, in particular the poor and the vulnerable, have equal rights to economic resources, as well as access to basic services, ownership and control over land and other forms of property, inheritance, natural resources, appropriate new technology and financial services, including microfinance </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.4.1
Proportion of population living in households with access to basic services
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.4.2
Proportion of total adult population with secure tenure rights to land, with legally recognized
documentation and who perceive their rights to land as secure, by sex and by type of tenure
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>
By 2030, build the resilience of the poor and those in vulnerable situations and reduce their exposure and vulnerability to climate-related extreme events and other economic, social and environmental shocks and disasters </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.5.1
Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.5.2

Direct disaster economic loss in relation to global gross domestic product (GDP)a
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.5.3
Number of countries with national and local disaster risk reduction strategies
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>
Ensure significant mobilization of resources from a variety of sources, including through enhanced development cooperation, in order to provide adequate and predictable means for developing countries, in particular least developed countries, to implement programmes and policies to end poverty in all its dimensions </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.a.1
Proportion of resources allocated by the government directly to poverty reduction programmes
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.a.2
Proportion of total government spending on essential services (education, health and social protection)
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>
Create sound policy frameworks at the national, regional and international levels, based on pro-poor and gender-sensitive development strategies, to support accelerated investment in poverty eradication actions </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>1.b.1
Proportion of government recurrent and capital spending to sectors that disproportionately benefit women, the poor and vulnerable groups
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                <aqd:query-line>TITLE-ABS-KEY (
                    (
                    ("poverty")
                    W/3
                    ("eradicat*" OR "reduc*" OR "end" OR "extreme" OR "alleviat*" OR "living" OR "life" OR "child*")
                    )
                    OR "social protection"
                    OR "economic marginalisation"
                    OR "poor and vulnerable"
                    OR ("resilien*" W/3 "the poor")
                    )
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:filters>
            <aqd:timerange field="PUBYEAR">
                <aqd:start>2009</aqd:start>
                <aqd:end>2019</aqd:end>
            </aqd:timerange>
        </aqd:filters>
    </aqd:query-definitions>
</aqd:query>
