<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="queries.xsl"?>
<aqd:query xmlns:dc="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-namespace/"
           xmlns:aqd="http://aurora-network.global/queries/namespace/">
    <dc:identifier type="sdg">13</dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier type="uri">http://metadata.un.org/sdg/13</dc:identifier>
    <icon>https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/content/images/E_SDG_Icons-13.jpg</icon>
    <dc:subject type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdg13</dc:subject>
    <dc:identifier type="version">5.0</dc:identifier>
    <dc:identifier type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817445</dc:identifier>
    <dc:source type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817443</dc:source>
    <dc:relation type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdgs</dc:relation>
    <dc:title>SDG-13 climate action</dc:title>
    <dc:description>
        Climate change is now affecting every country on every continent. It is disrupting national
        economies and affecting lives, costing people, communities and countries dearly today and even more tomorrow.
        Weather patterns are changing, sea levels are rising, weather events are becoming more extreme and greenhouse
        gas emissions are now at their highest levels in history. Without action, the world’s average surface
        temperature is likely to surpass 3 degrees centigrade this century. The poorest and most vulnerable people are
        being affected the most.
        Affordable, scalable solutions are now available to enable countries to leapfrog to cleaner, more resilient
        economies. The pace of change is quickening as more people are turning to renewable energy and a range of other
        measures that will reduce emissions and increase adaptation efforts. Climate change, however, is a global
        challenge that does not respect national borders. It is an issue that requires solutions that need to be
        coordinated at the international level to help developing countries move toward a low-carbon economy.
        To strengthen the global response to the threat of climate change, countries adopted the Paris Agreement at the
        COP21 in Paris, which went into force in November of 2016. In the agreement, all countries agreed to work to
        limit global temperature rise to well below 2 degrees centigrade. As of April 2018, 175 parties had ratified the
        Paris Agreement and 10 developing countries had submitted their first iteration of their national adaptation
        plans for responding to climate change.
    </dc:description>
    <dc:rights href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC-BY v4 INT</dc:rights>
    <dc:creator>Aurora Universities Network (AUR); René Otten (VUA); Eike Spielberg (UDE); Felix Schmidt (UDE); Maurice Vanderfeesten (VUA); Alessandro Arienzo (UNA); Roberto delle Donne (UNA); Ignasi Salvadó Estivill (URV); José Luis González Ugarte (URV); Didier Vercueil (UGA); Nykohla Strong (UAB); Eike Spielberg (UDE); Linda Hasse (UDE); Ane Sesma (UEA); Baldvin Zarioh (UIC); Friedrich Gaigg (UIN); Nicolien van der Grijp (VUA); Yasin Gunes (VUA); </dc:creator>
    <dc:contributor>Eike Spielberg (UDE); Peter van den Besselaar (VUA)
    </dc:contributor>
    <dc:date>2020-06-30</dc:date>
    <aqd:query-definitions syntax="SCOPUS">
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>0</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <dc:identifier type="uri">http://metadata.un.org/sdg/13.0</dc:identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description/>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    ( "climat*" W/3 "anthropogenic*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "action*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "adapt*" )
					OR ( "climat*" W/3 "biodiversity" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "carbon*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "change*" )
					OR ( "climat*" W/3 "crisis" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "deforestati*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "desertificati*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "ecolog*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "environment*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "GHG" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "global change" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "greenhouse gas*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "hazard*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "reforestati*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "variabilit*" )
                    OR ( "climat*" W/3 "warming" )
					OR ( "climat*" W/3 "water stress" )
					OR ( ( "climate" )  AND  ( ( "Paris" )  W/3  ( "agreement" OR "COP21" ) ) )  
					OR ( ( "climate" )  AND  ( ( "Kyoto" )  W/3  ( "protocol" ) ) )  
                    OR ( "climate action*" )
                    OR ( "Climate Effect*" )
                    OR ( "Climate Model*" )
                    OR ( "Climate Variability" )
                    OR ( "Climate Variation*" )
                    OR ( "climate-driven" )
                    OR ( "Climatology" )
                    OR ( "eco-innovation*" )
                    OR ( "environmental change*" )
                    OR ( "Environmental Impact" )
                    OR ( "Global Climate" )
                    OR ( "global warming" )
                    OR ( "Greenhouse Effect*" ) OR ( "Green-house Effect*" )
                    OR ( "Greenhouse Gas*" ) OR ( "Green-house Gas*" )
                    OR ( ( "sea level*") AND ( "chang*" OR "rising" ) )
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>1</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <dc:identifier type="uri">http://metadata.un.org/sdg/13.1</dc:identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    Strengthen resilience and adaptive capacity to climate-related hazards and natural disasters
                    in all countries
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.1.3
                    Proportion of local governments that adopt and implement local disaster risk reduction strategies in
                    line with national disaster risk reduction strategies
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.1.1
                    Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.1.2
                    Number of countries with national and local disaster risk reduction strategies
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    (( "climat*" OR "natural disaster*") W/3 "resilien*" )
					</aqd:query-line>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    ( "reduc*" )  W/3  ( "disaster*" )  W/3  ( "risk*" ) 
                </aqd:query-line>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                ( "disaster*" )  W/3  ( ( "number"  W/3  ( "death*"  OR  "people" ) )  OR  ( "missing person*" )  OR  ( "human loss*" ) )  
                </aqd:query-line>
				</aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>2</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <dc:identifier type="uri">http://metadata.un.org/sdg/13.2</dc:identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    Integrate climate change measures into national policies, strategies and
                    planning
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.2.1
                    Number of countries that have communicated the establishment or operationalization of an integrated
                    policy/strategy/plan which increases their ability to adapt to the adverse impacts of climate
                    change, and foster climate resilience and low greenhouse gas emissions development in a manner that
                    does not threaten food production (including a national adaptation plan, nationally determined
                    contribution, national communication, biennial update report or other)
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                 ( ( "climat*" )  W/3  ( "polic*"  OR  "strateg*" OR "plan"  OR  "plans"  OR  "planning" ) )  
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>3</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <dc:identifier type="uri">http://metadata.un.org/sdg/13.3</dc:identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    Improve education, awareness-raising and human and institutional capacity on
                    climate change mitigation, adaptation, impact reduction and early warning
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.3.1
                    Number of countries that have integrated mitigation, adaptation, impact reduction and early warning
                    into primary, secondary and tertiary curricula
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.3.2
                    Number of countries that have communicated the strengthening of institutional, systemic and
                    individual capacity-building to implement adaptation, mitigation and technology transfer, and
                    development actions
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				 ( "climate" )  W/3  ( "information"  OR  "awareness"  OR  "educat*"  OR  "teach*"  OR  "learn*" )  
                 </aqd:query-line>
				 </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>a</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <dc:identifier type="uri">http://metadata.un.org/sdg/13.a</dc:identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.a
                    Implement the commitment undertaken by developed-country parties to the United Nations Framework
                    Convention on Climate Change to a goal of mobilizing jointly $100 billion annually by 2020 from all
                    sources to address the needs of developing countries in the context of meaningful mitigation actions
                    and transparency on implementation and fully operationalize the Green Climate Fund through its
                    capitalization as soon as possible
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.a.1
                    Mobilized amount of United States dollars per year starting in 2020 accountable towards the $100
                    billion commitment
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				 ( "climate" )  W/3  ( "fund"  OR  "funds"  OR  "funding" OR "money"  OR  "dollar*" OR "commitment" OR "capitali*")  
                 </aqd:query-line>
				 <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				  ( "UNFCC"  OR  "United Nations Framework Convention for Climate Change" )   
                 </aqd:query-line>
				 </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>b</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <dc:identifier type="uri">http://metadata.un.org/sdg/13.b</dc:identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    Promote mechanisms for raising capacity for effective climate change-related
                    planning and management in least developed countries and small island developing States, including
                    focusing on women, youth and local and marginalized communities

                    * Acknowledging that the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change is the primary
                    international,
                    intergovernmental forum for negotiating the global response to climate change.
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    13.b.1
                    Number of least developed countries and small island developing States that are receiving
                    specialized support, and amount of support, including finance, technology and capacity-building, for
                    mechanisms for raising capacities for effective climate change-related planning and management,
                    including focusing on women, youth and local and marginalized communities
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				( "climate" )  AND  ( ( "assist*"  OR  "support*"  OR  "aid"  OR  "program*"  OR  "development*"  OR  "capacity*" )  
				W/3  ( "develop* countr*"  OR  "least developed countr*"  OR  "small island*" ) )  
                 </aqd:query-line>
				 </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:filters>
            <aqd:filter type="affilation" field="AF-ID"></aqd:filter>
            <aqd:timerange field="PUBYEAR">
                <aqd:start>2009</aqd:start>
                <aqd:end>2020</aqd:end>
            </aqd:timerange>
        </aqd:filters>
    </aqd:query-definitions>
</aqd:query>
