<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="queries.xsl"?>
<aqd:query xmlns:dc="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-namespace/"
           xmlns:aqd="http://aurora-network.global/queries/namespace/">
    <dc:identifier type="sdg">6</dc:identifier>
    <dc:subject type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdg6</dc:subject>
    <dc:identifier type="version">3.0</dc:identifier>
    <dc:identifier type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817437</dc:identifier>
    <dc:source type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817433</dc:source>
    <dc:relation type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdgs</dc:relation>
    <dc:title>SDG-06 clean water and sanitation</dc:title>
    <dc:description>Clean, accessible water for all is an essential part of the world we want to live in and there is sufficient fresh water on the planet to achieve this. However, due to bad economics or poor infrastructure, millions of people including children die every year from diseases associated with inadequate water supply, sanitation and hygiene.
Water scarcity, poor water quality and inadequate sanitation negatively impact food security, livelihood choices and educational opportunities for poor families across the world. At the current time, more than 2 billion people are living with the risk of reduced access to freshwater resources and by 2050, at least one in four people is likely to live in a country affected by chronic or recurring shortages of fresh water. Drought in specific afflicts some of the world’s poorest countries, worsening hunger and malnutrition. Fortunately, there has been great progress made in the past decade regarding drinking sources and sanitation, whereby over 90% of the world’s population now has access to improved sources of drinking water.
To improve sanitation and access to drinking water, there needs to be increased investment in management of freshwater ecosystems and sanitation facilities on a local level in several developing countries within Sub-Saharan Africa, Central Asia, Southern Asia, Eastern Asia and South-Eastern Asia.</dc:description>
    <dc:rights href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC-BY v4 INT</dc:rights>
    <dc:creator>
       Aurora Universities Network (AUR); René Otten (VUA); Lars Kullman (UGO); Maurice Vanderfeesten (VUA); Didier Vercueil (UGA); Nykohla Strong (UAB); Raf Guns (UAN); Felix Schmidt (UDE); Ane Sesma (UEA); Baldvin Zarioh (UIC);
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:contributor>
      Eike Spielberg (UDE)
    </dc:contributor>
    <dc:date>2019-05-31</dc:date>
    <aqd:query-definitions syntax="SCOPUS">
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>1</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
               <aqd:subquery-description>
          <!---->By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all</aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.1.1
Proportion of population using safely managed drinking water services
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>
          <!---->By 2030, achieve access to adequate and equitable sanitation and hygiene for all and end open defecation, paying special attention to the needs of women and girls and those in vulnerable situations </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.2.1
Proportion of population using safely managed sanitation services, including a hand-washing facility with soap and water
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>By 2030, improve water quality by reducing pollution, eliminating dumping and minimizing release of hazardous chemicals and materials, halving the proportion of untreated wastewater and substantially increasing recycling and safe reuse globally </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.3.1
Proportion of wastewater safely treated
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.3.2
Proportion of bodies of water with good ambient water quality
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>By 2030, substantially increase water-use efficiency across all sectors and ensure sustainable withdrawals and supply of freshwater to address water scarcity and substantially reduce the number of people suffering from water scarcity </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.4.1
Change in water-use efficiency over time
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.4.2
Level of water stress: freshwater withdrawal as a proportion of available freshwater resources
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>By 2030, implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including through transboundary cooperation as appropriate </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.5.1
Degree of integrated water resources management implementation (0-100)
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.5.2
Proportion of transboundary basin area with an operational arrangement for water cooperation </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>By 2020, protect and restore water-related ecosystems, including mountains, forests, wetlands, rivers, aquifers and lakes </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.6.1
Change in the extent of water-related ecosystems over time</aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>By 2030, expand international cooperation and capacity-building support to developing countries in water- and sanitation-related activities and programmes, including water harvesting, desalination, water efficiency, wastewater treatment, recycling and reuse technologies </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.a.1
Amount of water- and sanitation-related official development assistance that is part of a government-coordinated spending plan
                </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>Support and strengthen the participation of local communities in improving water and sanitation management </aqd:subquery-description>
        <aqd:subquery-description>6.b.1
Proportion of local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                <aqd:query-line>TITLE-ABS-KEY ((water) W/3 (quality OR ((safe OR affordable) AND (drink*))
                    OR ((use) AND (efficien*))OR harvest* OR ((waste OR resourc* OR sanitat*) AND manage*)
                    OR ((reduc*) AND (pollut*))OR (ecosystem*)))
                    TITLE-ABS-KEY(({water and sanitation})OR ({affordable drinking water})
                    OR ({Safe drinking water}) OR ({safe and affordable drinking water})
                    OR ({address water scarcity})OR ({improve water quality})
                    OR ({water-use efficiency}) OR ({water use efficiency}) OR ("water related ecosystems")
                    OR ({water harvesting}) OR ({water resource management})
                    OR ({sanitation management}) OR ({water and sanitation management})
                    OR ({reduce water pollution}) OR ({waste water management}) OR ({open defication})
                    OR (wastewater) OR ({sewage treatment}))
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:filters>
            <aqd:timerange field="PUBYEAR">
                <aqd:start>2009</aqd:start>
                <aqd:end>2019</aqd:end>
            </aqd:timerange>
        </aqd:filters>
    </aqd:query-definitions>
</aqd:query>
