<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="queries.xsl"?>
<aqd:query xmlns:dc="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-namespace/"
           xmlns:aqd="http://aurora-network.global/queries/namespace/">
    <dc:identifier type="sdg">4</dc:identifier>
    <icon>https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/content/images/E_SDG_Icons-04.jpg</icon>
    <dc:subject type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdg4</dc:subject>
    <dc:identifier type="version">5.0</dc:identifier>
    <dc:identifier type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817445</dc:identifier>
    <dc:source type="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3817443</dc:source>
    <dc:relation type="uri">https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdgs</dc:relation>
    <dc:title>SDG-04 quality education</dc:title>
    <dc:description>
        Obtaining a quality education is the foundation to creating sustainable development. In addition to
        improving quality of life, access to inclusive education can help equip locals with the tools required to
        develop innovative solutions to the world’s greatest problems.
        Over 265 million children are currently out of school and 22% of them are of primary school age. Additionally,
        even the children who are attending schools are lacking basic skills in reading and math. In the past decade,
        major progress has been made towards increasing access to education at all levels and increasing enrollment
        rates in schools particularly for women and girls. Basic literacy skills have improved tremendously, yet bolder
        efforts are needed to make even greater strides for achieving universal education goals. For example, the world
        has achieved equality in primary education between girls and boys, but few countries have achieved that target
        at all levels of education.
        The reasons for lack of quality education are due to lack of adequately trained teachers, poor conditions of
        schools and equity issues related to opportunities provided to rural children. For quality education to be
        provided to the children of impoverished families, investment is needed in educational scholarships, teacher
        training workshops, school building and improvement of water and electricity access to schools.
    </dc:description>
    <dc:rights href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC-BY v4 INT</dc:rights>
    <dc:creator>Aurora Universities Network (AUR); René Otten (VUA); Eike Spielberg (UDE); Felix Schmidt (UDE); Maurice Vanderfeesten (VUA); Alessandro Arienzo (UNA); Roberto delle Donne (UNA); Ignasi Salvadó Estivill (URV); José Luis González Ugarte (URV); Didier Vercueil (UGA); Nykohla Strong (UAB); Eike Spielberg (UDE); Linda Hasse (UDE); Ane Sesma (UEA); Baldvin Zarioh (UIC); Friedrich Gaigg (UIN); Nicolien van der Grijp (VUA); Yasin Gunes (VUA); </dc:creator>
    <dc:contributor>Eike Spielberg (UDE); Peter van den Besselaar (VUA)
    </dc:contributor>
    <dc:date>2020-06-30</dc:date>
    <aqd:query-definitions syntax="SCOPUS">
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>1</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys complete free, equitable and quality primary and
                    secondary education leading to relevant and effective learning outcomes
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.1.1
                    Proportion of children and young people: (a) in grades 2/3; (b) at the end of primary; and (c) at
                    the end of lower secondary achieving at least a minimum proficiency level in (i) reading and (ii)
                    mathematics, by sex
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    (( "inclusi*" OR "equit*" ) AND
                    ( "quality education" ))
                 </aqd:query-line>
				 <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    (( "Quality" OR "equitabl*" OR "free" OR "access" OR "affordab*") W/3
                    ( "Primary education" OR "primary school" OR "secondary education" OR "secondary school"))
                 </aqd:query-line>
				 <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    ( "proficiency level" W/3
                    ( "reading" OR "mathematics" ))
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition>
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>2</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys have access to quality early childhood development,
                    care and pre-primary education so that they are ready for primary education
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.2.1
                    Proportion of children under 5 years of age who are developmentally on track in health, learning and
                    psychosocial well-being, by sex
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.2.2
                    Participation rate in organized learning (one year before the official primary entry age), by sex
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    ( "Quality" OR "equitabl*" OR "free" OR "access" OR "affordab*") W/3
                    ( "preschool" OR "pre-school" OR"pre-primary education" OR "pre-primary school" OR "preprimary education" OR "preprimary school")
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>3</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, ensure equal access for all women and men to affordable and quality
                    technical, vocational and tertiary education, including university
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.3.1
                    Participation rate of youth and adults in formal and non-formal education and training in the
                    previous 12 months, by sex
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				("equal" OR "equit*") W/3 ("access") W/3 ("tertiary education" OR "university" OR "vocational education" )
                </aqd:query-line>
        </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>4</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, substantially increase the number of youth and adults who have
                    relevant skills, including technical and vocational skills, for employment, decent jobs and
                    entrepreneurship
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.4.1
                    Proportion of youth and adults with information and communications technology (ICT) skills, by type
                    of skill
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                    (( "increas*" W/3 ("skills" OR "competenc*")) AND ( "employ*" OR "decent job*" OR "entrepreneur*" ))
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>5</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, eliminate gender disparities in education and ensure equal access to
                    all levels of education and vocational training for the vulnerable, including persons with
                    disabilities, indigenous peoples and children in vulnerable situations
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.5.1
                    Parity indices (female/male, rural/urban, bottom/top wealth quintile and others such as disability
                    status, indigenous peoples and conflict-affected, as data become available) for all education
                    indicators on this list that can be disaggregated
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
                ( ("gender disparit*" OR "gender parit*" OR "gender inequalit*" OR "gender equalit*") AND "educat*")
				</aqd:query-line>
                 <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">  
                 ( ( "vulnerable" OR "disabilit*" OR "disabled" OR "indigen*" ) W/3 "educat*" )
				</aqd:query-line>	
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				( ( "girl*"  OR  "women" )  AND  ( "equal*"  W/3  "educat*" ) )  
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>6</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, ensure that all youth and a substantial proportion of adults, both
                    men and women, achieve literacy and numeracy
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.6.1
                    Percentage of population in a given age group achieving at least a fixed level of proficiency in
                    functional (a) literacy and (b) numeracy skills, by sex
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">"literacy" OR "numeracy" OR  "reading skill*"  OR  "writing skill*"
				</aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>7</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, ensure that all learners acquire the knowledge and skills needed to
                    promote sustainable development, including, among others, through education for sustainable
                    development and sustainable lifestyles, human rights, gender equality, promotion of a culture of
                    peace and non-violence, global citizenship and appreciation of cultural diversity and of culture’s
                    contribution to sustainable development
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.7.1
                    Extent to which (i) global citizenship education and (ii) education for sustainable development,
                    including gender equality and human rights, are mainstreamed at all levels in: (a) national
                    education policies, (b) curricula, (c) teacher education and (d) student assessment
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( ( "sustainable development" )  W/3  ( "educat*"  OR  "teach*" OR  "learn*" ) )
				</aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>a</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    Build and upgrade education facilities that are child, disability and gender
                    sensitive and provide safe, non-violent, inclusive and effective learning environments for all
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.a.1
                    Proportion of schools with access to: (a) electricity; (b) the Internet for pedagogical purposes;
                    (c) computers for pedagogical purposes; (d) adapted infrastructure and materials for students with
                    disabilities; (e) basic drinking water; (f) single-sex basic sanitation facilities; and (g) basic
                    handwashing facilities (as per the WASH indicator definitions)
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">("school facilit*")
				</aqd:query-line>
			  <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( "school*" )  W/3  ( "access" )  W/3  ( "electricity"  OR  "internet"  OR  "computer*" )
				</aqd:query-line>
			  <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( "school*" )  W/3  ( "drinking water"  OR  "sanitation"  OR  "handwashing*" OR  "hand washing*")
				</aqd:query-line>
				</aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>b</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2020, substantially expand globally the number of scholarships available to
                    developing countries, in particular least developed countries, small island developing States and
                    African countries, for enrolment in higher education, including vocational training and information
                    and communications technology, technical, engineering and scientific programmes, in developed
                    countries and other developing countries
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.b.1
                    4.b.1
                    Volume of official development assistance flows for scholarships by sector and type of study
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( "scholarships" )  AND  ( "develop* countr*"  OR "least developed countr*" OR  "small island*" )
				</aqd:query-line>
                 <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">( "scholarships" )  W/6  ( "South Africa"  OR  "Sub-Saharan Africa"  OR  "Equatorial Africa"  OR  "West Africa" )
				</aqd:query-line>
				</aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:query-definition syntax="SCOPUS">
            <aqd:subquery-identifier>c</aqd:subquery-identifier>
            <aqd:subquery-descriptions>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    By 2030, substantially increase the supply of qualified teachers, including
                    through international cooperation for teacher training in developing countries, especially least
                    developed countries and small island developing States
                </aqd:subquery-description>
                <aqd:subquery-description>
                    4.c.1
                    Proportion of teachers in: (a) pre-primary; (b) primary; (c) lower secondary; and (d) upper
                    secondary education who have received at least the minimum organized teacher training (e.g.
                    pedagogical training) pre-service or in-service required for teaching at the relevant level in a
                    given country
                </aqd:subquery-description>
            </aqd:subquery-descriptions>
            <aqd:query-lines>
                <aqd:query-line field="TITLE-ABS-KEY">
				(( "teacher*" ) W/3 ("training" OR "qualified" OR "education") ) AND ( "develop* countr*" OR "least developed countr*" OR "small island*" )
                </aqd:query-line>
            </aqd:query-lines>
        </aqd:query-definition>
        <aqd:filters>
            <aqd:filter type="affilation" field="AF-ID"></aqd:filter>
            <aqd:timerange field="PUBYEAR">
                <aqd:start>2009</aqd:start>
                <aqd:end>2020</aqd:end>
            </aqd:timerange>
        </aqd:filters>
    </aqd:query-definitions>
</aqd:query>
